Qunliang Xing

37 Xueyuan Road Haidian District, Beijing, China ryanxingql@gmail.com https://ryanxingql.github.io

Introduction

Qunliang Xing received the BEng degree and Honors degree from Beihang University, Beijing, China in 2019. He is currently pursuing the Ph.D. degree at Beihang University, advised by Changjiang Distinguished Professor Mai Xu. His research interests include image/video enhancement and coding. He has published several papers in IEEE TPAMI and ECCV, one of which is top 1% highly cited according to the essential science indicators (ESI). He has won two NTIRE championships. His open-source projects have received more than 600 stars. He is selected for Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program. He is awarded OpenMMLab Active Contributor. He has won the second place in the Beihang 100m final and the Beihang soccer championship as the school team captain. He is a reviewer for several IEEE transactions including TIP, TMM, TCSVT and JAS.

Education

Beihang University, Beijing, China	Sept. 2019 – Present
Ph.D. student	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Ph.D. Student	Shen Yuan Honors College
Beihang University, Beijing, China	Sept. 2015 – July 2019
Bachelor of Engineering	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Bachelor	Shen Yuan Honors College
Nanshan Foreign Language School, Shenzhen, Cl	Sept. 2012 – July 2015
Admitted to Beihang University with the highest score in	n Guangdong Province. High School

Selected Publications

[1] DAQE: Enhancing the Quality of Compressed Images by Exploiting the Inherent Characteristic of Defocus Qualiang Xing, Mai Xu, Xin Deng, Yichen Guo

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2023)

[2] Progressive Training of A Two-Stage Framework for Video Restoration
Qunliang Xing, Meisong Zheng, Minglang Qiao, Mai Xu, Lai Jiang, Huaida Liu, Ying Chen
IEEE / CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops (2022)
Technical report of our winning method in the NTIRE challenge.

[3] DeepQTMT: A Deep Learning Approach for Fast QTMT-Based CU Partition of Intra-Mode VVC Tianyi Li, Mai Xu, Runzhi Tang, Ying Chen, Qunliang Xing IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (2021)

[4] Patent CN111415311: Resource-saving Image Quality Enhancement Model Mai Xu, Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan China National Intellectual Property Administration (2020)

[5] Early Exit Or Not: Resource-Efficient Blind Quality Enhancement for Compressed Images Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Tianyi Li, Zhenyu Guan European Conference on Computer Vision (2020)

[6] MFQE 2.0: A New Approach for Multi-Frame Quality Enhancement on Compressed Video

Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan, Mai Xu, Ren Yang, Tie Liu, Zulin Wang

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2019)

Highly cited paper (Top 1%) by Essential Science Indicators (ESI).

Work Experience

Reviewer Feb. 2021 – Present

IEEE Journals and Conferences

• ĬEEE TIP, IEEE TMM, IEEE TCSVT, IEEE/CAA JAS, IEEE ICME

Research Internship on Video Quality Enhancement

Dec. 2021 - Present

Tao Technology, Alibaba Group

• Winning two championships and one runner-up in the NTIRE 2022 challenge.

Participant in Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program

July 2021 – Sept. 2021

Tencent

• Selected among the top 127 out of 1,800+ candidates.

Mentor of Undergraduates

Oct. 2020 - Oct. 2021

Shen Yuan Honors College, Beihang University

• Awarded the Shen Yuan Excellent Mentor (Top 9/36).

Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Beihang University

• Introduction to Machine Learning.

Research on Video Quality Enhancement of HW265 Codec

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2019

2012 Lab, Huawei

• Improving the RD performance of HW265 by 10%.

Awards & Honors

Two Championships and One Runner-up		
NTIRE Challenge on Super-Resolution and Quality Enhancement of Compressed Video		2022
Glarun Scholarship		
The 14TH Research Institute, China Electronics Technology Group Corporation	(CETC)	2022
Beihang Outstanding/Merit Student		
Beihang University	2022, 2021, 2018,	2015
Second Place in the 100m Final		
Beihang Sports Day, Beihang University		2022
Shen Yuan Excellent Mentor		
Shen Yuan Honors College, Beihang University		2021
Beihang Excellent Graduate		
Beihang University		2019
Soccer Championship (Starting CB)		
Beihang Sports Festival, Beihang University		2017
Shenzhen Merit Student		
Education Bureau of Shenzhen Municipality		2014